[{"id": "600241484be4723ccac22174", "question": "What famous author tried to get his wife committed to an insane asylum so he could live with his 18-year-old mistress?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6000f14a9a72b906b34e3d03", "question": "What kind of animal is a bantam?", "answer": "Chicken -- A true bantam is a breed of chicken that is naturally small.  The male has a reputation for being very aggressive.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6008ddb0f4f3bc4a292f8623", "question": "After World War II, who was the first leader of the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia?", "answer": "Ivan Ribar (From December 29. 2945 until January 14, 1953, he was the President of the Federal Assembly of Yugoslavia.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6b", "question": "Who was the number 1 ranked male tennis player the most years during the 1970\u2019s?", "answer": "Jimmy Connors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c274", "question": "What is July's birthstone?", "answer": "Ruby", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133995b", "question": "Robert Englund played the main villain in what series of horror films?", "answer": "A Nightmare on Elm Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c42e", "question": "What period saw the first dinosaurs?", "answer": "Triassic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b323740bf195a31e15d73c3", "question": "Lisbon lies on which river?", "answer": "Tagus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f4c", "question": "How many syllables are there in Japanese haiku?", "answer": "Seventeen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f753da9e54d890926f707", "question": "How long is New Zealand\u2019s Ninety Mile Beach?", "answer": "55 miles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac71", "question": "Where were scissors believed to be first invented?", "answer": "Ancient Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb1", "question": "What title was given to Nanak, the founder of Sikhism?", "answer": "Guru", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f2a1ff048f679a45aaba", "question": "What do you call an organ that produces gametes?", "answer": "Gonad", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c49e", "question": "What word describes the habit of some bears for sleeping through the winter?", "answer": "Hibernation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c753fbde8045e48466c1", "question": "What is the scientific name of the plant used to make liquorice?", "answer": "Glycyrrhiza glabra, the plant used to make liquorice, is native to Europe and Asia.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f9f4e82af848b908361b882", "question": "What year was Pinterest launched?", "answer": "2010", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d9842596a59cbdfbd3c6", "question": "U.S. Marshal Bass Reeves may have inspired what fictional character?", "answer": "The Lone Ranger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb0", "question": "Which American female flyer disappeared without a trace over the Pacific in 1937?", "answer": "Amelia Earhart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a1a3d212f2a7826b9b8729", "question": "What is the atomic number for Palladium?", "answer": "46", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ed", "question": "What is the inflammation of the stomach and small intestine called?", "answer": "Gastroenteritis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af91", "question": "Who was assassinated by Leon Czolgosz?", "answer": "President William McKinley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff670f552a821ff76ae8b23", "question": "Who invented \"Jell-O\"?", "answer": "Pearle Wait", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87f", "question": "What four letters are directly to the right of \"Q\" on a standard keyboard?", "answer": "W, E, R, T", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339762", "question": "In what movie does an office worker's hypnotherapy go wrong?", "answer": "Office Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a5da20565ad31a57c7d2", "question": "What image was on the world's first jigsaw puzzle?", "answer": "A map", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdffcc31cf6db9ac4808d03", "question": "What is the longest bridge in the San Francisco Bay Area?", "answer": "San Mateo-Hayward Bridge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c19b", "question": "Which British driver was Formula One World Champion in 1996?", "answer": "Damon Hill", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb6", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Cape Codder?", "answer": "Cranberry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592eae6df83302ff91e46488", "question": "What bird lays an egg that is roughly a quarter of its body weight?", "answer": "The Kiwi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d116744fea7fe947a22270", "question": "Who played the role of Veronica Quaife in the 1986 film \"The Fly\"?", "answer": "Geena Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338970", "question": "What century did Rembrandt live in?", "answer": "17th", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b871", "question": "What prominent facial feature is Hello Kitty missing?", "answer": "Mouth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87a", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"La Rambla\"?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c107", "question": "What fruit is used in making \"Creme de Cassis\"?", "answer": "Blackcurrants\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917c", "question": "What is the name of the actor who plays Dexter Morgan on the TV show \"Dexter\"?", "answer": "Michael C. Hall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339667", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who is Lisa's teacher?", "answer": "Miss Hoover", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a99f", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Nyiragongo\"?", "answer": "The Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c61b", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Lead?", "answer": "Pb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b3", "question": "N2O is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "Laughing gas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6002447a4be4723ccac221a4", "question": "How long did it take Leonardo da Vinci to paint the Mona Lisa's smile?", "answer": "Leonardo's greatest triumph was the smile of the Mona Lisa, which he labored on for 16 years up until his death.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a095", "question": "What was the name of Punky Brewster's dog?", "answer": "Brandon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0e3affcbed638185eaa24", "question": "A building called \"The Gherkin\" graces which city's skyline?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea4531ff048f679a45ab91", "question": "What type of muscle bends a joint in the body?", "answer": "Flexor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5d726ce05a3942286e2b", "question": "Which hit song is Norman Greenbaum known for?", "answer": "\"Spirit in the Sky\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af29", "question": "The Kenyan terrorists fighting for independence in the 50\u2019s were known as who?", "answer": "The Mau Mau", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3ed7b8b5801b8f54a7fb2", "question": "When did the U.S. Postal Service release its first Christmas stamp?", "answer": "1962", "category": "history"}, {"id": "595247c2736d4be723796b73", "question": "What is the name of Lady Antebellum\u2019s first #1 hit?", "answer": "\"I Run To You\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd3b97e83c707845b2154", "question": "How many noble houses of Westeros are there in \"Game of Thrones\"?", "answer": "Nine (Arryn, Baratheon, Greyjoy, Lannister, Martell, Stark, Targaryen, Tully and Tyrell)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65620ae7e414034b5aec1", "question": "Dionysus was the Greek god of what?", "answer": "Wine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc8d36de0eb824d4052ff", "question": "Which two European countries are located along Turkey\u2019s northwestern border?", "answer": "Greece and Bulgaria -- Turkey also borders three central Asian countries, as well as, three Middle Eastern countries.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173c3444491cbd7c5a17a4", "question": "What collectively-named languages evolved from Vulgar Latin?", "answer": "Romance or romanic language -- The five most spoken romance languages are Spanish, French, Portuguese, Italian and Romanian.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f81", "question": "What was Billy J. Kramer's backing band?", "answer": "The Dakotas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b26", "question": "In \"Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs\", which dwarf's job is it to check the authenticity of the gems they mine?", "answer": "Doc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab151dbaab681b0929217a", "question": "What year marked the inaugural season of Formula One?", "answer": "1950", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cb53bb53d1af658864d7", "question": "In the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", how many drummers are drumming?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdc11c0469bb8041d07a079", "question": "What is the name of a popular Italian orange and vanilla flavored liqueur?", "answer": "Tuaca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95e", "question": "At what age does a filly become a mare in thoroughbred horse racing?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58be2d038faf425cf37add7a", "question": "In Greek mythology, which of the nine Muses is normally depicted sitting down and holding a lyre?", "answer": "Terpsichore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f6", "question": "What cut of steak got its name from the New York City coach stop where it was first served?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cdd69e347d002c297e4f0", "question": "What are affected by Phylloxera?", "answer": "Grapevines", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff51487ff04d658268c92e3", "question": "What Spartan king led a small army of 300 Spartans against a vastly superior Persian force in the Battle of Thermopylae?", "answer": "Leonidas, King of Sparta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a07", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the band Audioslave?", "answer": "Chris Cornell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ea", "question": "What US state has been led by Theodore and Franklin Roosevelt?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c341", "question": "How many ventricles does the brain have?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0dc07fcbed638185eaa0b", "question": "Where was the first Disney theme park outside the U.S. built?", "answer": "Tokyo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a19e", "question": "Who sang \"You Can Call Me Al\"?", "answer": "Paul Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be1d", "question": "What is the setting for the video game Fallout 3?", "answer": "Capital Wasteland/Washington D.C.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b571b9e67df192a942e336b", "question": "Who first appeared in the novel \"The Mysterious Affair at Styles\"?", "answer": "Hercule Poirot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ff", "question": "Lucille Fay LeSueur became famous as who?", "answer": "Joan Crawford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a431", "question": "The remains of which ancient city are found in Iraq?", "answer": "Babylon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b734", "question": "Spotted dick is a traditional British confection of boiled suet pudding with what?", "answer": "Raisins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cefc19f948005ec986edce7", "question": "What powers Iron Man's suit?", "answer": "Arc reactor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b614", "question": "First marketed in 1952, Pream was a brand of instant what?", "answer": "Creamer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f93", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Sayonara\"?", "answer": "Miyoshi Umeki", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e8", "question": "The \"Robots in Disguise\" are better known as what?", "answer": "Transformers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133944d", "question": "Who narrates the movie \"Lock, Stock and Two Smoking Barrels\"?", "answer": "Alan Ford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e93e06d333868d34d753", "question": "Where is the mythological birthplace of the Incas?", "answer": "Isla del Sol, Bolivia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a271", "question": "Who played the character of Paul Bratter in the 1967 film \"Barefoot in the Park\"?", "answer": "Robert Redford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb9fa7e83c707845b2141", "question": "In the film \"The Shawshank Redemption,\" how long does Red spend in prison before being paroled?", "answer": "40 years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd8", "question": "In Arthurian legend, what was the name of King Arthur's magic sword?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded323ea2747c8aff16d45", "question": "What is a \"Sam Browne\"?", "answer": "Military belt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febad0d7e83c707845b20f0", "question": "Which element is named for a mischievous spirit from German folklore?", "answer": "Cobalt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00a", "question": "What was \"Ponch\"s real first name on CHiPs?", "answer": "Frank", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bef2", "question": "In which English city would you find The Christmas Steps?", "answer": "Bristol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b571bdc67df192a942e336e", "question": "What is the name of the farm in the book \"Animal Farm\"?", "answer": "Manor Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ff", "question": "What are you doing if you \"yarn over\" or \"pop corn\"?", "answer": "Knitting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfcae9dc5ec6cd98a831e", "question": "What artist's work was involved in a case before the New York Supreme Court in 2010?", "answer": "Julie Mehretu's\u00a0work was the object of a case which involved legal issues over her work and the right of first refusal contracts.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2cf8c2596a59cbdfbd370", "question": "Who said, \u201cThe secret of happiness, you see, is not found in seeking more, but in developing the capacity to enjoy less\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a4", "question": "What fruit is grown extensively on Cape Cod?", "answer": "Cranberries", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ce", "question": "A tetrapod is a creature with how many feet?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65db11f3c0ead6880d61f", "question": "Where was the treaty signed ending the Russo-Japanese War?", "answer": "Portsmouth, New Hampshire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5da8543f1aec824685d88cfe", "question": "In a speech in liberated Paris in 1944, Winston Churchill said, \"be on your guard, because I am going to...\" do what?", "answer": "Speak French", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7ec7cb24f84e0b9f9ffe7", "question": "Who made the song \"Bad Case of Loving You\" popular?", "answer": "Robert Palmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3d", "question": "The 2002 film \"Confessions of a Dangerous Mind\" was based on the unauthorized autobiography of what former gameshow host?", "answer": "Chuck Barris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb28", "question": "In baseball score-keeping, what number represents the third baseman's position?", "answer": "5", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339959", "question": "Who played Frankenstein\u2019s monster in the 1931 movie \"Frankenstein\"?", "answer": "Boris Karloff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c248", "question": "Which is larger, the U.S. gallon or the Imperial gallon?", "answer": "The Imperial", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7e", "question": "What British holiday is celebrated on December 26th?", "answer": "Boxing Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b68a", "question": "What company introduced the first automatic washing machine at the Louisiana State Fair in 1937?", "answer": "Bendix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c18b", "question": "Vinnie Jones was associated with which sport?", "answer": "Soccer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339482", "question": "Who directed the 1969 movie \"The Wild Bunch\"?", "answer": "Sam Peckinpah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd19", "question": "What vegetable is found in dishes served \"Florentine\" style?", "answer": "Spinach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b912", "question": "\"Benjamins\" is slang for what denomination of US currency?", "answer": "$100", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b995", "question": "What car company introduced the Pinto in the 1970s?", "answer": "Ford Motor Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aead", "question": "Who was known as the Welsh Wizard?", "answer": "David Lloyd George", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad69", "question": "The first cable car in the world began service in 1873 in what city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a378", "question": "What is the capital of Finland?", "answer": "Helsinki", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a459", "question": "The Bermuda Triangle is located in what ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a899bb860d398dc9cf7a6a0", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the Pelican State?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff66d0252a821ff76ae8b16", "question": "What item was banned by the U.S. government in 1943 due to a paper shortage?", "answer": "Sliced bread (Among other reasons, sliced bread required twice as much wax paper as unsliced bread.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3893c73aa70ea0b70ad3", "question": "The San Blas Islands are part of which Central American nation?", "answer": "Panama", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f8", "question": "Which English director founded the Theatre Workshop?", "answer": "Joan Littlewood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b8", "question": "In the TV show \"Knight Rider\", what was the real last name of Michael Knight?", "answer": "Long", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be89", "question": "What type of a tree killed Jackson Pollock?", "answer": "Oak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a17", "question": "Jamie Somers became \"The Bionic Woman\" following emergency surgery after what type of accident?", "answer": "Parachuting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0aa", "question": "What Nazi Field Marshall was known as \"The Desert Fox\"?", "answer": "Erwin Rommel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ee", "question": "What did Edward Teach modify by adding an hourglass and a spear?", "answer": "The Jolly Roger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb4", "question": "What was first presented at Hollywood\u2019s Roosevelt Hotel on May 16, 1929?", "answer": "The Academy Awards (Oscars)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af258c7b63e5727cf5a4848", "question": "Who co-produced the song \"Summertime\" with Will Smith?", "answer": "DJ Jazzy Jeff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c9", "question": "The March of Dimes was originally founded to help find a vaccine for what?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c41b", "question": "What is the common word for a weight suspended from a pivot that can move freely?", "answer": "A pendulum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339770", "question": "What movie features the four high school friends Jim, Finch, Oz and Kevin?", "answer": "American Pie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c599", "question": "What fungus is used in making bread?", "answer": "Yeast", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fffa74c73838c5c8a417f36", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3bd", "question": "In which country did the Boxer Rebellion take place?", "answer": "China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1bd", "question": "What US president was a personal friend of John Kenneth Galbraith?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f0cfff048f679a45aaa7", "question": "Tonitrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Thunder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5e", "question": "For what does the \"F.\" stand in the name F. Lee Bailey?", "answer": "Francis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a551b63e1c6f9840ba318e", "question": "Which country owns the island of Corfu?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c350", "question": "What object is theorized to lie at the center of the Milky Way?", "answer": "A black hole", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a19", "question": "What nationality was Vincent van Gogh?", "answer": "Dutch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab77", "question": "Mauritius is part of which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e95", "question": "Whose first book was the 2006 memoir \"Peace Mom\"?", "answer": "Cindy Sheehan's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e72c93ad0874f1a5e2d1c1d", "question": "How many shower curtain rings does the typical shower curtain have?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf49", "question": "What is the next-to-last event?", "answer": "Penultimate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ef", "question": "What two US states have the word \"Mountain\" in their official nicknames?", "answer": "West Virginia and Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca49", "question": "American Garrett Morgan patented what in 1923?", "answer": "The Traffic Signal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb65", "question": "What horse won the 2012 Kentucky Derby and Preakness Stakes?", "answer": "I'll Have Another", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c021", "question": "Which fashion designer was shot dead in the summer of 1997?", "answer": "Gianni Versace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedda536ce05a3942286d84", "question": "Brothers Barry, Robin and Maurice Gibb formed which successful pop group in the late 1950's?", "answer": "Bee Gees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bac8fb6c85e9e634ff52", "question": "What is the name for the group of men who elect a Pope?", "answer": "College of Cardinals", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45a", "question": "Who led over 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1978?", "answer": "Jim Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34c", "question": "What is the world's widest river?", "answer": "The Amazon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a582", "question": "Prudence Island is the third largest island in which US state?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51c", "question": "What is Whisky distilled from?", "answer": "Fermented grain mash", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c13b", "question": "Who said \"You'd be surprised how much it costs to look this cheap\"?", "answer": "Dolly Parton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae9503574a5ce6b56b824f", "question": "Lilongwe is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e03", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Persephone?", "answer": "Proserpine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae07", "question": "What was the first living creature to go into orbit?", "answer": "A dog", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f7", "question": "Which is the largest state in the US?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eb17cf83302ff91e464a8", "question": "What cartoon by Mike Judge is the 1999 film \"Office Space\" based on?", "answer": "Milton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b1a401dd7bf43be5e793", "question": "What was the original name of the Popsicle?", "answer": "Eppsicles (Eppsicle was named after its creator, Frank Epperson.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8e", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Robert Van Winkle?", "answer": "Vanilla Ice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008d9c9f4f3bc4a292f8612", "question": "What was the British royal family known as before becoming the House of Windsor?", "answer": "Up until 1917, the Royals were known as the Saxe-Coburgs (and sometimes as the Saxe-Coburg-Gothas).", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5921fed8a4edfd43a087add2", "question": "What currency was used in the Netherlands before the introduction of the Euro?", "answer": "Guilders", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945f", "question": "How does Jack die in the movie \"The Shining\"?", "answer": "He freezes to death", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c131877e98cb97778975", "question": "Where is Grant\u2019s Tomb?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd96dac23c87fd04dd15e2d", "question": "Who was the first person to fly around the world alone?", "answer": "Wiley Hardeman Post", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a272", "question": "Who played the character of Corie Bratter in the 1967 film \"Barefoot in the Park\"?", "answer": "Jane Fonda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c3", "question": "What hit 1992 movie gave Geena Davis the chance to prove she could spit?", "answer": "A League of their Own", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed1", "question": "Which US state was the first to secede from the Union in 1860?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a311", "question": "Which 1970's sci-fi film featured a space ship named \"Nostromo\"?", "answer": "Alien", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d6", "question": "In The Simpsons, when Ned Flanders started his own store, he quit his job as what?", "answer": "Pharmaceuticals salesman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b65", "question": "How many of the seven dwarfs have beards?", "answer": "6", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a7", "question": "In what year did the San Francisco 49ers become the first five-time Super Bowl champs?", "answer": "1995", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339adb", "question": "What 1984 #1 song by the duo Wham! charted again in 2009 when covered by the group Seether?", "answer": "Careless Whisper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b421", "question": "Who was the first Chancellor of the Federal Republic of Germany?", "answer": "Konrad Adenauer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baee", "question": "NAFTA is a trade agreement between the US and what other two countries?", "answer": "Mexico and Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede5546ce05a3942286dea", "question": "What Bruce Willis action movie takes place on Christmas eve?", "answer": "\"Die Hard\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b6", "question": "Who became \"king of the cowboys\" when Gene Autry entered the army in WWII?", "answer": "Roy Rogers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca00", "question": "What is the technical term for an organism that eats other organisms as food?", "answer": "A heterotroph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd86", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, King Ghidorah?", "answer": "Three-headed dragon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a3", "question": "In which decade were the first Winter Olympic Games held?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a0", "question": "What 1989 Billy Joel hit was included in Junior Scholastic magazine as an educational aid?", "answer": "We Didn't Start the Fire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e93517ccba3ffe45786c4", "question": "What word is used to describe \"bell shaped flowers\"?", "answer": "Campanulate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f86cfe83fe1f2a824c2d", "question": "Passover is celebrated around the same time with a Christian holiday. What Christian holiday is this?", "answer": "Easter Passover is usually celebrated in March or April, which is around the same time Christians also celebrate Easter.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062afcc9d816e292245c1c", "question": "What American artist preferred to call his sculptures \"structures\"?", "answer": "Sol LeWitt\u00a0came to fame in the late 1960s with his wall drawings and \"structures\" but was prolific in a wide range of media.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca5", "question": "Who wrote the science-fiction novel \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd4ca7e83c707845b2160", "question": "In the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\", which character had his hands replaced by the director, Frank Darabont, as insert shot?", "answer": "Andy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca80", "question": "In what country was margarine first patented?", "answer": "France", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601370e11381754895396386", "question": "What baseball player had the nickname \"Sultan of Swat\"?", "answer": "George Herman \"Babe\" Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907d", "question": "What controversial book did Germaine Greer write?", "answer": "The Female Eunuch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f16", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Robert Downey and Eddie Izzard?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3924c73aa70ea0b70ad8", "question": "Explorers named Rhode Island after resemblance to which part of the world?", "answer": "The Greek island, Rhodes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133937e", "question": "Where were the first Academy Awards held at?", "answer": "The Roosevelt Hotel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b200", "question": "Whose US presidential campaign was targeted by the famous \"Daisy Girl\" negative TV ad?", "answer": "Barry Goldwater's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cacf877e98cb97778a0c", "question": "Which Arab country houses the Rub Al-Khali or Empty Quarter, the largest continuous sand desert in the world?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e96917ccba3ffe45786ef", "question": "Galt MacDermot wrote the music for what 1967 musical?", "answer": "Hair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e147775dd42e4a67cb8d3ea", "question": "What is the name of Weird Al Yankovic's 1989 feature film?", "answer": "UHF", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339324", "question": "In the 1992 movie \"Sister Act\", what is the name of Whoopi Goldberg's character who gets put under protection?", "answer": "Deloris van Cartier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1ecbc145fb29466707388", "question": "Where did fondue originate?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a943", "question": "What does \"Lo Stivale\", the local name for the Italian peninsula, mean in Italian?", "answer": "The boot", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa40", "question": "What country's explorers discovered the site of Pensacola, Florida?", "answer": "Spain's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600243bf4be4723ccac2219b", "question": "What is the name of Emily Bronte\u2019s only completed novel?", "answer": "Wuthering Heights", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a362", "question": "What US city's skyline boasts the Gateway Arch?", "answer": "St. Louis'", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c046", "question": "Which world champion was beaten by a machine called Deep Blue in 1997?\u00a0", "answer": "Gary Kasparov", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ff", "question": "What South American country is home to Atacama Desert?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339836", "question": "Who won a Grammy Award for her song \"Killing Me Softly\"?", "answer": "Roberta Flack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1d", "question": "The Scottish outlaw Robert Roy MacGregor was better known as?", "answer": "Rob Roy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399cf", "question": "What famous blind musician has the real given last name Judkins?", "answer": "Stevie Wonder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb2", "question": "Whom did rapper Chuck D fire from Public Enemy in 1989 for making anti-Semitic comments?", "answer": "Professor Griff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392bb", "question": "Which sitcom was set in the offices of the fictional magazine \"Blush\"?", "answer": "Just Shoot Me", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25bb8b63e5727cf5a485b", "question": "What year did the British band EMF release the hit single \"Unbelieveable\"?", "answer": "1990", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eba", "question": "What happens to Neo twice in a row that clues Trinity in to a glitch in the movie \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "A black cat passes him", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b937364247bf200fb889", "question": "Who made the song \"A Boy Named Sue\" popular in 1969?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339293", "question": "What 2007 film follows the crew of the Icarus II as they attempt to reignite a falling sun?", "answer": "Sunshine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339374", "question": "Which \"Saturday Night Fever\" cast member was nominated for an Oscar?", "answer": "John Travolta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7d058877e98cb97778a5f", "question": "What is the name of the largest glacier in the world?", "answer": "Lambert-Fisher", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b07", "question": "What is the name of the Wally World mascot in \"National Lampoon's Vacation\"?", "answer": "Marty Moose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eda", "question": "What trumpet-like horn is jazz-man Chuck Mangione's instrument?", "answer": "The flugelhorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e1", "question": "Who devised the towering framework that supports the \"The Statue of Liberty\"?", "answer": "Alexandre-Gustave Eiffel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b229", "question": "What city was Anton Cermak killed in?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cf4e877e98cb97778a4d", "question": "What is the largest borough of New York City?", "answer": "Queens", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21c", "question": "What city was Wild Bill Hickok killed in?", "answer": "Deadwood", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b9d", "question": "Who was the last king of Troy killed by Achilles son Pyrrhus?", "answer": "Priam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfcf", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"S\"?", "answer": "Sierra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49a", "question": "What year was the UK an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1908", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0bd", "question": "What three words did George Bush say before \"no new taxes\" in 1988?", "answer": "Read my lips", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91a", "question": "The word alphabet comes from which 2 Greek letters?", "answer": "Alpha and Beta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69c6f20565ad31a57c76c", "question": "The \"Era of Good Feelings\" is associated with the administration of which president?", "answer": "James Monroe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af53", "question": "During World War II, who was the \"Desert Fox\"?", "answer": "Field Marshall Rommell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339046", "question": "What year did Wagner compose \"Tannhauser\"?", "answer": "1845", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fee", "question": "Which famous artist designed the Chupa Chups logo in 1969?", "answer": "Salvador Dali", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c214877e98cb97778985", "question": "What is the smallest borough of New York City by land area?", "answer": "Manhattan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe1ec09145fb29466707384", "question": "In which country is Stilton cheese produced?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133992d", "question": "What TV show featured the radio station KACL 780 AM?", "answer": "Frasier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd9a", "question": "What kind of lunch is the common British pub meal of a piece of Cheddar, crusty bread, and a pickle?", "answer": "Ploughman's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a303", "question": "Who was Randy Mario Poffo better known as?", "answer": "\"Macho Man\" Randy Savage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c57", "question": "What is the name of Sergeant Snorkle\u2019s dog in \u201cBeetle Bailey\u201d?", "answer": "Otto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdab5230b8cce1e6fda704a", "question": "Which popular coffee drink is named after hooded monks?", "answer": "Cappuccino", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33a", "question": "What actress played 4 roles in the 1975 film \"Trilogy of Terror\"?", "answer": "Karen Black", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede4e26ce05a3942286de3", "question": "Who recorded the hit single \"Sussudio\" in 1985?", "answer": "Phil Collins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cb70bfcf96e155acab35d27", "question": "What is Chiroptophobia?", "answer": "Fear of Bats", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010c8c10775fa611bce67e3", "question": "\"Mano a mano\" translates to what?", "answer": "Hand to hand -- It originates from the world of Spanish bullfighting and refers to any sort of competition, argument, or fight.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ba", "question": "What did Freud call the female counterpart of the Oedipus complex?", "answer": "The Elektra complex", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3b0", "question": "What is a better known name for the Hellenic Republic?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133899b", "question": "The John Knowles novel \"A Separate Peace\" is narrated by which character?", "answer": "Gene", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d1184b4fea7fe947a22283", "question": "What is the correct name for brown coal?", "answer": "Lignite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a4", "question": "Natalie Coughlin won six medals in what sport at the 2008 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Swimming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea434aff048f679a45ab81", "question": "Which type of rhinoceros is the largest on average?", "answer": "White", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c028d55ea32143fcb1d3b58", "question": "In which state is Walla Walla County located?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a91b", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Benning?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5aab2eb858d116dab4aecb41", "question": "Who played the role of Wayne Szalinski in the 1989 film \"Honey, I Shrunk the Kids\"?", "answer": "Rick Moranis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c24", "question": "Who wrote \"The Star-Spangled Banner\"?", "answer": "Francis Scott Key", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b718", "question": "Citizens of what empire are credited with starting the tradition of gift giving?", "answer": "Romans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be9", "question": "Which instrument does the Leader of an orchestra play?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a745", "question": "Which is the fourth largest US state in surface area?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c54", "question": "Whitney Houston's self-titled debut album was released in what year?", "answer": "1985", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f23", "question": "Which Old Master signed his paintings with his full Cretan name, Dom\u00e9nikos Theotok\u00f3poulos?", "answer": "El Greco", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f3", "question": "What type of food is Lollo Rosso?", "answer": "Lettuce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049ac5cf93664eb104869a", "question": "Comic book writer and artist Jack Kirby, was given what name at birth?", "answer": "Jacob Kurtzberg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b330", "question": "Where were the 1988 Olympics held?", "answer": "Seoul, South Korea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133979c", "question": "How many Oscars did \"The Color Purple\" collect from its 11 nominations?", "answer": "None", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133892d", "question": "In which comic book series did Galactus first appear?", "answer": "The Fantastic Four", "category": "arts"}]